This is getting messy...
I better hurry up and use this thing.
（サソリ）
さすがに 面倒になってきたな
さっさと これ使うか
（春野はるのサクラ）あっ…
（チヨ）ん…
As I thought, that puppet...
uses the Third's Jutsu...!
やはり その傀儡くぐつ
三代目の術を
You haven't seen this in
a while, have you...?
久しぶりだろ
This Jutsu is why the Third Kazekage
was praised as the most powerful.
この術で三代目風影かぜかげは
最強とうたわれたんだからな
I'm gonna turn you guys into mush.
２人とも ぐちゃぐちゃだぜ
What the hell is that?
一体 何？
That was the most feared weapon
of the Hidden Sand.
あれは 砂隠すながくれで
最も恐れられた武器
The Iron Sand.
砂鉄さてつじゃ
Iron Sand...?
“砂鉄”？
The Third developed that Jutsu
かつての守鶴しゅかくの所有者が
用いた術を応用して
by basing it on the Jutsu used
by the former Shukaku wielder.
三代目が みずから開発した術での
It changes the Iron Sand
into various shapes,
あらゆる形状に 砂鉄を変化させ
状況に応じた武器を作り出す
creating weapons according
to the situation.
The Third Kazekage had a special body
三代目風影は
練り込んだチャクラを
磁力に変えることができる...
that could change the Chakra
into magnetism.
特別な体質だった
Similarly, it appears that puppet
同じように あの傀儡も
also can change the Chakra
into magnetism.
チャクラを磁力に
変えることができるようじゃ
What do you mean?
どういうことです？
Even though the actual body of
The Third Kazekage was used,
三代目風影自身の
肉体を使ったとはいえ
it's still just a doll, right?
あれが ただの人形であることに
変わりはないでしょ
Why does a doll have the Chakra?
どうして 人形にチャクラが…
No... A Human Puppet made
from an actual living body
いや 生身の人体から作った人傀儡は
is fundamentally different
from these normal ones
この父と母のような
普通の傀儡人形とは根本的に違う
like the "mother" and
"father" puppets.
A Human Puppet can only
be made by Sasori...
人傀儡は サソリにしか作れない
and that is made while
the living Chakra still is embodied.
そして それは生前のチャクラを
宿したままに作られるのじゃ
あっ…
And by doing so, it can use the person's
Jutsu from its previous life.
そして それによって
生前のその者の術を扱うことができる
That's the biggest benefit
of the "Human Puppet".
それが 人傀儡の
最大の利点でもあるのじゃ
That's not all.
それだけじゃないぜ
After all,
this is my favorite collection.
なんせ 俺の
お気に入りコレクションだからな
Sakura, get out of here.
（チヨ）サクラ
お前は ここから外に出ろ
あっ
I will take care of the rest.
あとは わし一人でやる
ええっ？
そんな これは想定外すぎる
This is way too unexpected.
That Puppet makes it impossible for you.
あれが出た以上 お前では無理じゃ
But!
でも…
You're too slow!
（サソリ）遅いんだよ！
Iron Sand: Scattered Showers!
砂鉄時雨さてつしぐれ！
（サクラ）あっ！
Oh shoot!
（チヨ）まずい！
あっ
フッ 少しはいじってるじゃねえか
Did you alter it a little?
A Chakra shield, huh?
チャクラの盾とはな
Looks like it's been upgraded
俺が遊んでたころよりは
グレードアップしてるようだな
compared to the time
I was playing with them.
ハア ハア…
はっ
As expected, due to
the Iron Sand, my moves...
（チヨ）やはり 砂鉄で身動きが…
フッフフ
Don't you know that you have to dodge
this Jutsu and not shield it?
この術は防ぐんじゃなく
かわさないとダメだって
知ってんだろ
Seems like you could barely
let the chick go.
小娘を 逃がすだけで
手いっぱいだったか
フッフフ
ああ…
I inserted the Iron Sand
into his entire body.
（サソリ）そいつの体じゅうに
砂鉄を潜り込ませた
As long as I have the Third's magnetism,
that one's done for.
こっちに三代目の磁力がある以上
もう そいつはダメだぜ
うっ…
Let's see... I will aim at both
of you and attack at once.
（サソリ）
さて… 今度は２人を狙って
一斉に攻撃する
In order to ensure an definite kill,
I will form it into a lethal weapon.
確実にしとめるため
殺傷能力重視の形状にしてな
あっ
I won't let you get away
a second time...
二度と逃がしはしない
With only one puppet,
you can't guard the both of you.
１つの傀儡じゃ
２人いっぺんにはガードできないぞ
What are you going to do, Grandma?
どうする？ ババア
（チヨ）うっ…
（サソリ）フフッ
（サクラ）あっ…
Who is gonna die?!
（サソリ）どっちが死ぬ？
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Father and Mother
うっ…
あっ
（チヨ）ハア ハア…
（サソリ）
腕とはいえ 己の体のカラクリ化
Though only the arm...
Turning your own body into a puppet...
（チヨ）ハア…
傀儡使いという人種どうし
考えることも同じだな
As fellow Puppet Masters,
it seems... we think the same way.
（チヨ）はっ… ううっ
フフフ…
フッ…
どういうことじゃ
What's going on?
（チヨ）
昔のまま 年を取っておらぬ
He's the same as before...
He hasn't aged.
そうか そういうことか
I see. I get it now...
あっ…
砂鉄が入り込んだら もう終わりだ
It's the end if the Iron Sand gets in.
傀儡も尽きた
Let's see...
The puppet has ceased.
どうする？ チヨバア
What are you going to do,
Grandma Chiyo?
バ… バカな
I-Impossible...
Damn you...
おのれ…
木こノ葉はの白しろい牙きばめ
White Fang of the Leaf...!
（男の子）アハハ…
（チヨ）ん？
（幼少期のサソリ）あっ…
（チヨ）サソリ
Sasori...
あっ…
ん？
チヨバア様
Grandmother Chiyo, please buy me
snacks on the way back.
帰りに お菓子を買ってくださいね
あっ ああ…
Yeah... why not...
そうじゃなあ
（物音）
（幼少期のサソリ）ん？
えっ？
あっ… ハハッ
チヨバア様
Grandmother Chiyo.
どうじゃ サソリ
How is it, Sasori...?
わが家に 代々伝わる傀儡の術じゃ
This is the Puppet Master Jutsu
passed down
from generation to generation.
覚えてみようとは思わんかね
Don't you want to learn it?
えっ 教えてもらえるの？
Huh?! Can you teach me?
では 一緒に来るがいい
Now... come with me.
ん？
ここに並ぶのは
砂隠れの里で作られた...
Lined up here are the prototype
and incomplete puppets made
in the Hidden Sand Village.
傀儡の試作品や失敗作じゃ
（チヨ）サソリ
（幼少期のサソリ）ん？
Sasori...
ここにあるものは自由に使うがよい
You can use everything here,
why don't you make your own puppet?
自分の傀儡を作ってみよ
えっ？ 自分の傀儡
My own puppet?
（チヨ）こ… これは
Th-This is...!
ああ…
（チャクラ糸が切れる音）
（幼少期のサソリ）あっ！
フッ 天下の傀儡使いも
The world's best Puppet Master
is just a human
傀儡がなけりゃ ただの人か
without the puppets, huh.
わしともあろう者が
How could I let this...?
さて この状況… どうしたものか
Now then, what should
I do with this situation?
フッ
Sakura... In any case, you need to go!
サクラ ともかくお前は逃げろ
サクラ
Sakura? What's wrong?
Hurry up!
どうした？ 早くしろ
言ったであろう
I told you...
that it is impossible for you.
あれは お前では無理じゃ
わしが なんとか
食い止めているうちに
I will take care of this...
So run!
逃げるのじゃ
Run?
（サクラ）逃げる？
チヨバア様を置いて 私一人で
Leaving Granny Chiyo...
and me alone...?
No, there should be something...
いえ 何かあるはず
There should be something
even I can do.
今の私にも 何かできることが
What I can do now...?
今の私にできること それは…
That is...
Grandmother Chiyo...
（サクラ）チヨバア様
（チヨ）ん？
Please use me!
私を使ってください
えっ？
What I can do now...
（サクラ）今の私にできること
それは チヨバア様の傀儡になって
戦うことぐらい
is to become Grandmother Chiyo's
puppet and fight.
（サクラ）生身の私を使えば
砂鉄で動きを封じることはできません
If you use me, he can't stop
my moves with the Iron Sand.
I am left with one arm.
（チヨ）わしは今 片腕じゃ
さっきほどのサポートはできんぞ
I can't support you like before.
大丈夫です
I'm okay...
確かに 私には…
True, I don't have a great weapon
like the puppet, but...
傀儡みたいに立派な武器は
仕込んでありませんが
師匠譲りの負けん気が
Like my master, I have guts!
嫌というほど
仕込んでありますから
あっ…
Princess Tsunade, huh...
（チヨ）綱手(つなで)姫か フッ…
（チヨ）三代目の能力は磁力じゃ
The Third's power is magnetism.
Therefore, weapons made from
iron and steel won't work.
よって 鉄や鋼でできた武器は効かぬ
Excellent! I am also like my master
when it comes to fighting with the fist.
上等！
素手で戦うのも師匠譲りです
That again... Ridiculous.
またそれか くだらない
くっ…
あっ！
ううっ
いくぞ！
Here I go!
はあーっ！
（サソリ）うっ
You...
こいつ…
Here I come!
まだまだ これから！
♪～
Just like always.
daitai itsumo doori ni
As I turn that corner.
sono kado wo magareba
I am lost in the waves of people.
hitonami ni magire komi
Melting, disappearing.
tokete kiete iku
I lose my way.
boku wa michi wo nakushi
I even completely lose my words.
kotoba suranaku shite shimau
But just one thing.
dakedo hitotsu dake wa
Remained, remained.
nokotteta nokotteta
Your voice.
kimi no koe ga
Your smiling faces, your angry faces, everything.
warau kao mo okaru kao mo subete
Keeps me walking on.
boku wo arukaseru
Surely, when I see the point where the clouds have broken.
kumo ga kireta saki wo mitara kitto nee
You know what I mean?
wakaru desho
nee wakaru desho
～♪
Next Episode
Naruto Shippuden is
becoming more exciting.
ますます盛り上がる「ナルト疾風伝しっぷうでん」
次回はついに
In the next episode, my beloved
Sakura-san is in big trouble.
僕の愛するサクラさんが 大ピンチ
Plus, Sasori...
しかも サソリが…
番組の途中ですが 緊急速報です
Sorry to interrupt,
but there is breaking news.
川かわの国くに中部を震源とする
局地的な地震がありました
There was a local earthquake
centered on the river country.
一部で 洞窟が
崩落する被害が出ています
A cave has collapsed in some areas.
継続して
余震が続いておりますので
Aftershocks are still continuing
so please be cautious.
今後の揺れに
十分注意してください
うわっ 大変です
Ah, Oh no, due to that news, our preview comment got--
今の速報のせいで
僕たちの
予告コメントが…
The Third Kazekage
What? Then let's try this one more time...
なんだって？
では 気を取り
直してもういち…
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
（チャイム）
Today is about Medical Ninjutsu.
Now then, shall we start?
（サクラ）
きょうは 医療忍術についてよ
それでは授業を始めましょ
Medical Ninjutsu is when
you affect the body with
膨大な専門知識と
繊細なチャクラコントロールで
a massive amount specialty knowledge
and delicate chakra control.
人体に働きかける医療忍術
There are many jutsu that are used
for treating injuries and poison,
ケガや毒の
治療に使う術が多いけど
but other jutsu are used
in battle to attack,
チャクラのメスで攻撃したり
相手の神経系を
狂わせるといった...
like the chakra scalpel.
It can also ruin
an opponent's nervous system.
戦闘に使える術もあるのよ
The ultimate ninjutsu is Master Tsunade's
“Ninja Art: Mitotic Regeneration”.
中でも究極の忍術が
綱手師匠の忍法創造再生そうぞうさいせい
大量のチャクラで 細胞の分裂を早め
You can heal any injury quickly
by increasing cell division with
large amounts of chakra.
どんな傷でも
すぐに治してしまえるけど
However, it comes at a huge cost-
it shortens one's life.
寿命を縮めてしまうという
大きな代償を伴うの
Now, here is a question.
さて ここで問題
Which is Tsunade-sama's assistant,
Shizune-san?
綱手様の付き人
シズネさんはどれでしょう
The correct answer is C.
（サクラ）正解は…
I need to train more and
私も もっと修行して
シズネさんや師匠のような
become a first-class Medical Ninja
like Shizune-san and my master. Shannaro!
一流の医療忍者にならなきゃね
しゃーんなろー！
Oh no... I've done it.
あっ やっちゃった